the following is a conversation with
以下是 与之 对话
guido van rossum creator of Python one
guido van rossum 是Python的 创造者 之一
of the most popular programming
最流行的节目
languages in the world used in almost
几乎所用 的世界语言
any application that involves computers
任何涉及计算机的应用程序
from web back-end development to
从Web后端开发到
psychology neuroscience computer vision
心理学神经科学计算机视觉
and robotics deep learning natural
和机器人深度学习 自然
language processing in almost any
几乎任何 语言处理
subfield of AI this conversation is part
AI的子领域这个对话是其中的一部分
of MIT course on artificial general
麻省理工学院 人工综合 课程
intelligence and the artificial
智力和人工
intelligence podcast if you enjoy it
智能播客，如果你喜欢它
subscribe on YouTube iTunes or your
订阅YouTube iTunes 或您的
podcast provider of choice or simply
播客提供商的选择或简单
connect with me on Twitter at lex
在 lex 上在Twitter上与我联系
friedman spelled FR ID and now here's my
弗里德曼拼写FR ID ，现在这里是我的
conversation with guido van rossum you
与 guido van rossum交谈 你
were born in the Netherlands in 1956
1956年出生于荷兰
your parents and the world around you
你的父母和你周围的世界
was deeply impacted by world war ii as
第二次世界大战深深影响为
was my family from the soviet union so
是我的家人从 苏联 这样
with that context well what is your view
有了这样的背景，你的观点是什么
of human nature are some humans
人性 是一些人类
inherently good and some inherently evil
本质上是好的和一些天生的邪恶
or do we all have both good and evil
或者我们都有 善恶
within us ouch I did not expect such a
在我们哎哟我没 想到这样 的
deep one I I guess we all have good and
我猜所有人 都很好
evil potential in us in a lot of it
在我们的邪恶潜力不少呢
depends on circumstances in context out
取决于具体情况
of that world at least on the Soviet
那个世界，至少在苏联
Union side in Europe sort of out of
在欧洲的联盟方面 有点 出局
suffering out of challenge out of that
因此受到挑战
kind of set of traumatic events often
经常 发生一些创伤事件
emerges beautiful art music literature
出现美丽的艺术音乐文学
in an interview I read or heard you said
在一次 采访中我读到或听到你说过
you enjoy Dutch literature when when you
当你的时候，你喜欢荷兰文学
were a child can you tell me about the
小时候你可以告诉我这个
books that had an influence on you in
对你有影响的书
your childhood
你的童年
well as a teenager my favorite writer
以及作为 青少年我最喜欢的作家
was my favorite Dutch author was a guy
是我最喜欢的荷兰作家是一个人
named villain Phaedra chemins whose
名为恶棍的Phaedra chemins
writing
写作
certainly his early novels were all
他的早期小说当然都是
about sort of ambiguous things that
关于那些含糊不清的东西
happened during World War two I think he
发生 在第二次世界大战期间 我认为他
was a young adult during that time and
那个时候是一个年轻的成年人
he wrote about it a lot and and very
他写了很多而且非常
interesting very good books I thought I
有趣的非常好的书，我以为我
think in a nonfiction way no it was all
以非虚构的方式思考并不是全部
fiction but it was very much set in in
小说， 但它非常适合
the ambiguous world of resistance
暧昧的抵抗世界
against the Germans where often you
经常对你的德国人
couldn't tell whether someone was truly
无法判断某人是否真的
in the resistance or really a spy for
在电阻或真的是间谍
the Germans and and some of the
德国人和一些人
characters in his novels sort of crossed
他小说中的人物有点交叉
that line and you never really find out
这条线，你永远不会发现
what exactly happened and in his novels
究竟 发生了什么，在他的小说中
there's always a good guy and a bad guy
总有一个好人和一个坏人
the nature of good and evil is it clear
善恶的本质是明确的
there's a hero it's no his heroes are
有一个英雄， 这 不是他的英雄
often more his main characters are often
他的主要角色往往更多
anti-heroes and and and so there they're
他们是 反英雄等等
not not very heroic they're they're
他们不是非常英雄
often they they fail at some level to
通常他们会在某种程度上失败
accomplish their lofty goals and looking
实现他们崇高的目标 和期待
at the trajectory through the rest of
在通过其余部分的轨迹
your life has literature Dutch or
你的生活有文学荷兰语或
English or translation and an impact
英语或翻译和影响
outside the technical world that you
在技​​术世界之外，你
existed in
存在于
I still read novels I don't think that
我还读小说，我不这么 认为
it impacts me that much directly doesn't
它直接影响了我
impact your work it's just it's uh it's
影响你的工作只是 它呃 它
a separate world my work is is highly
一个独立的世界， 我的工作是高度的
technical and sort of the the world of
技术和世界的
art and literature doesn't really
艺术和文学 并不是真的
directly have any bearing on it you
直接对你有任何影响
don't think there's a creative element
不要以为有创意 元素
to the design you know some would say
对于你知道有人会说的设计
our design of a language is art I'm not
我们的语言设计是艺术，我不是
disagreeing with that I'm just saying
不同意我只是说
that sort of I don't feel direct
那种我 感觉不直接
influences from more traditional art on
从更传统的现有技术的影响
my own creativity right of course you
我自己的 创造力 当然是 你
don't feel doesn't mean it's not somehow
不觉得并不意味着它不是以某种方式
deeply there and your subconscious knows
在那里，你的潜意识知道
who knows so let's go back to your early
谁知道呢，让我们 回到 你的早期
teens your hobbies were building
青少年你的爱好正在建设中
electronic circuits building mechanical
电子电路建筑机械
models what if you could just put
模拟你可以放的东西
yourself back in the mind of that young
你自己回到 那个年轻人 的脑海里
Guido 12 13 14 was that grounded in a
Guido 12 13 14 是以a。为基础的
desire to create a system so to create
渴望创建一个系统以便创建
something or was it more just tinkering
什么或者 更像是修修补补
just the joy of puzzle solving uh I
拼图的只是喜悦 解决 呃我
think it was more the leather actually I
认为这是更皮革其实 我
maybe towards the end of my high school
也许 在 我高中 结束 时
period I felt confident enough that that
期间， 我觉得足够 有 信心
I designed my own circuits that were
我设计了自己的电路
sort of interesting somewhat
有点有趣
but a lot of that time I literally just
但很多时候我真的只是
took a model kit and follow the
拿了一个模型套件并 按照
instructions putting the things together
说明把事情放在一起
I mean that I think the first few years
我的意思是我认为最初的几年
that I build electronics kits I really
我 真的在 制作电子产品 包
did not have enough understanding of
对此没有足够的 了解
sort of electronics to really understand
一种 真正理解 的电子产品
what I was doing I mean I could debug it
我在做什么 我的意思是 我可以调试它
and I could sort of follow the
而且我可以 跟随
instructions very carefully which has
非常仔细的说明
had which has always stayed with me but
曾经一直和 我在一起但是
I had a very naive model of like how a
我有一个非常天真的模型，如何一个
transistor works and I don't think that
晶体管的工作，我不认为
that in those days I had any
在那些日子里，我 有任何
understanding of coils and capacitors
了解线圈和电容器
which which actually sort of was a major
哪个实际上是一个主要的
problem when I started to build more
当 我开始建造更多的 问题
complex digital circuits because I was
因为我是 复杂的数字 电路
unaware of the sort of the analog part
不知道那种 模拟部分
of the how they actually work and I
他们实际工作的方式和我
would have things that the scheme the
会有这个计划的东西
schematic looked every everything looked
原理每次看着看着一切
fine and it didn't work and what I
很好，它 不起作用，我
didn't realize was that there was some
没有意识到 有一些
megahertz level oscillation that was
兆赫级的振荡，这是
throwing the circuit off because I had a
抛弃电路，因为我有一个
sort of two wires were too close or the
两根电线太近或者太近了
switches were were kind of poorly built
交换机有点糟糕
but through that time I think it's
但到那时我觉得是的
really interesting and instructive to
非常有趣和有益
think about because as echoes of it are
想想因为 它 的 回声
in this time now so in the 1970s the
在这个时候现在所以在20世纪70年代
personal computer was being born
个人电脑诞生了
so did you sense in tinkering with these
所以你觉得修补这些
circuits did you sense the encroaching
电路你感觉到了侵犯
revolution and personal computing so if
革命和个人计算如果
at that point you're sick we will see
那时你会生病我们会看到
you down and ask you to predict the 80s
你失望并要求你预测80年代
and the 90s do you think you would be
而且你认为你会成为 90年代
able to do so successfully to unroll
能够成功 地展开
this the process that's no I had no clue
这一点， 没有这个过程中我根本不知道
I I
II
remember I think in the summer after my
记得我认为 在夏天之后 我
senior year or maybe it was the summer
高年级或者也许是夏天
after my junior year well at some point
在我大三的时候，在某些 时候
I think when I was 18 I went on a trip
我想我18岁的时候去旅行了
to the Math Olympiad in Eastern Europe
参加东欧 的数学奥林匹克运动会
and there was like I was part of the
就像我是其中的一部分
Dutch team and there were other nerdy
荷兰队还有其他的书呆子
kids that sort of had different
有点不同的孩子
experiences and one of them told me
经验 和其中一个告诉我
about this amazing thing called a
关于这个 惊人的事情叫做
computer and I had never heard that word
电脑，我从来没有听过 这个词
my own explorations in electronics were
我自己在电子方面的探索是
sort of about very simple digital
有点非常简单的数字
circuits and I I had sort of I had the
电路 和II有点 我有
idea that I somewhat understood how a
想法，我有点理解如何
digital calculator worked hmm and so
数字计算器工作嗯等
there is maybe some echoes of computers
可能还有一些计算机的回声
there but I didn't didn't I never made
那里，但我没有，我从来没有做过
that connection I didn't know that when
这个联系我什么时候不知道
my parents were paying for magazine
我的父母正在为杂志买单
subscriptions using punched cards that
订阅使用穿孔卡
there was something called a computer
有一种叫做电脑的东西
that was involved that read those cards
这是涉及 读取这些卡
and transferred the money between
并转移了 钱
accounts that was also not really
帐户也不 是真的
interested in those things it was only
感兴趣的那些东西 也就只有
when I went to university to study math
我上大学读数学的时候
that I found out that they had a
我发现他们有一个
computer and students were allowed to
电脑和学生被允许
use it and there were some you're
使用它 ，有一些你
supposed to talk to that computer by
应该通过 交谈 到 该计算机
programming it what did that feel like
它的编程了 什么 是 感觉
yeah that was the only thing you could
是的，这是 你 唯一 能做到的
do with it
做它
I think the computer wasn't really
我觉得电脑 不是真的
connected to the real world the only
连接到现实世界的唯一
thing you could do was sort of you typed
你可以做的事就是你输入的那种
your program on a bunch of punched cards
你的程序在一堆打孔卡上
you gave the punched cards to the
你把穿孔卡给了
operator and an hour later the operator
操作员和一小时后的操作员
gave you back your printout and so all
给你打印出来的所有内容
you could do was write a program that
你能做的就是编写一个程序
did something very abstract and I don't
做了一些非常抽象的事情 而我却没有
even remember what my first forays into
甚至还记得 我的第一次尝试
programming were
编程是
but they were sort of doing simple math
但他们有点简单的数学
exercises and just to learn how a
练习，只是学习 如何
programming language worked did you
编程语言工作了吗？
sense ok first year of college you see
感觉好大学第一年你看
this computer you're able to have a
这台电脑你能 拥有一 台电脑
program and it generates some output did
程序， 它产生一些输出
you start seeing the possibility of this
你开始看到这种可能性
or was it a continuation of the
还是它的延续？
tinkering with circuits the did you
修补你的 电路
start to imagine that one the personal
开始想象一个人的个人
computer but did you see it as something
电脑， 但 你有没有看到它
that is a tool so got a tool like a word
这是一个工具，所以有一个像一个单词的工具
processing tool maybe maybe for gaming
处理工具也许可能用于游戏
or something or did you start to imagine
或某事或你开始想象
that it could be you know going to the
它可能是你 知道去 的
world of robotics
机器人 世界
like you you know the Franklin is that
像你一样，你知道富兰克林 就是这样
picture that you could create an
你可以创建的图片
artificial being there's like another
人工存在就像另一个人
entity in front of you you did not say I
在你面前的实体你没有说我
don't think I really saw it that way I
不要以为 我真的那样看待我
was really more interested in the
真的对此更感兴趣
tinkering it's maybe not a sort of a
修补它可能不是一种
complete coincidence that I ended up
完全巧合，我结束了
sort of creating a programming language
有点像创建编程语言
which is a tool for other programmers
这是其他程序员的工具
I've always been very focused on the
我 一直非常专注于
sort of activity of programming itself
编程本身的一些活动
and not so much what happens with with
而不是与之相关的事情
the program you write right I do
你写的程序我做的正确
remember and I don't dream it maybe in
记得我不 ，也许 做梦了
my second or third year probably my
我的第二年或 第三年 可能是 我的
second actually someone pointed out to
第二个实际上有人指出
me that there was this thing called
我有 这个叫做的东西
Conway's Game of Life you're probably
你 可能是 康威的生命游戏
familiar with it I think the seventies I
熟悉它我认为七十年代我
think yeah he came up with it so there
想想啊，他想出了 这么有
was a scientific American column by
是一个科学的美国 专栏
someone who did a monthly column about
每月专栏的人
mathematical diversions
数学转移
I'm also blanking out on the guy's name
我也在说这个人的名字
it was it was very famous at the time
这是它在 当时 非常有名
and I think up to the 90s or so and one
我想到了 90年左右和一个
of his columns was about Conway's Game
他的专栏是关于康威的游戏
of Life and he had some illustrations
生活和他有一些插图
and he wrote down all the rules
他写下了所有 的规则
and sort of there was the suggestion
有点建议
that this was philosophically
这是哲学
interesting that that was why Conway had
有趣的是，这就是康威的原因
called it that and all I had was like
称它是所有我曾经很 喜欢
the two pages photocopy of that article
那篇文章 的两页复印件
I didn't even remember where I got it
我甚至不 记得我在哪里得到 它
but it spoke to me and I remember
但 它告诉 我，我记得
implementing a version of that game for
实现该 游戏 的版本
the batch computer we were using where I
我在哪里使用的批处理计算机
had a whole Pascal program that sort of
有一个整体的Pascal程序之类的
read an initial situation from input and
从输入和读取初始情况
read some numbers that that said do so
读一些那些说过的数字
many generations and print every so many
许多世代和印刷品都是如此之多
generations and then out would come
几代人 然后 出来了
pages and pages of sort of things kinds
各种各样的 页面和页面
of different kinds and yeah and I
不同种类 ，是的和我
remember much later I've done a similar
记得很久以后我做了类似的事
thing using Python but I'd sort of that
使用Python的东西， 但我会那样
original version I wrote at the time I
我 当时 写的原版
found interesting because I combined it
发现很有趣，因为 我结合了它
with some trick I had learned during my
我在学习期间学到了一些技巧
electronics hobbyists times I
电子爱好者时代 我
essentially first on paper I designed a
基本上首先在纸上我设计了一个
simple circuit built out of logic gates
由逻辑 门 构建的简单电路
that took nine bits of input which is
该输入了9位是
the sort of the cell and its neighbors
细胞及其邻居的种类
and produced a new value for that cell
并为该单元格 生成了新值
and it's like a combination of a half
它就像是 一半 的组合
adder and some other clipping you know
加法器和其他一些你知道的剪辑
it's actually a full adder and so I had
它实际上是一个 完整的加法器，所以我有
worked that out and then I translated
努力工作，然后我翻译
that into a series of boolean operations
进入一系列布尔运算
on Pascal integers where you could use
在你可以使用的Pascal整数上
the integers as bitwise values and so I
整数作为按位值，所以我
could basically generate 60 bits of a
基本上可以生成60位的a
generation in in like eight instructions
在八个指令中产生
or so
或者
nice I was proud of that it's it's funny
我很自豪，这很有趣
that you mentioned so for people who
你提到的 那些人
don't know Conway's Game of Life is a
不知道康威的生命游戏是 一个
there's it's a cellular automata whether
这是一个细胞自动机是否
it's single compute units that kind of
这是一个计算单位的那种
look at their neighbors and figure out
看看他们的邻居并弄清楚
what they look like in the next
他们 在下一个 看起来 像 什么
generation based on the state of their
基于 他们 的状态 的 一代
neighbors and this is deeply distributed
邻居， 这是深刻的分布
system that it in in concept at least
它至少在概念上的系统
and then there's simple rules that all
然后就是 所有 的简单规则
of them follow and somehow out of this
他们跟随并以某种方式离开了这个
simple rule when you step back and look
退后一步看简单的规则
at what occurs it's it's beautiful
在什么事情发生 它是美丽的
there's a emergent complexity even
甚至 还有一种紧急的复杂性
though the underlying rules are simple
虽然基本规则很简单
there's an emergent complexity now the
现在有一个紧急的复杂性了
funny thing is you've implemented this
有趣的是你已经实现了 这一点
and the thing you're commenting on is
而你评论的是
you're proud of a hack you did to make
你为自己所做的黑客感到骄傲
it run efficiently when you're not
当你不是时， 它会有效地运行
commenting on what like this is a
评论这是什么样的
beautiful implementation you're not
美丽的实施你不是
commenting on the fact that there's an
评论有一个 事实
emergent complexity that you've you've
您已经拥有的紧急复杂性
you've coded a simple program and when
你编写了一个简单的程序，何时编写
you step back and you print out those
你退后一步打印出来
following generation after generation
一代又一代
that's stuff that you may have not
那些 你可能 没有 的东西
predicted what happen is happening right
预测会发生什么事情 正确 发生
and there was that is that magic I mean
那是我的意思
that's the magic that all of us feel
这就是我们所有人都感受到的魔力
when we program when you when you create
当我们在您创建时编程时
a program and then you run it and
一个程序 ，然后你运行它
whether it's hello world or show
无论是hello world还是show
something on screen if there's a
屏幕上有东西，如果有的话
graphical component for you seeing the
你看到 的图形组件
magic in the mechanism of creating that
在 创造这种机制的 魔力
I think I went back and forth as a
我想我来回走 了
student we had an incredibly small
学生我们有一个非常小的
budget of computer time that we could
我们可以预算的计算机时间
use it was actually measured I once got
使用它实际上是我曾经测过的
in trouble with one of my professors
与我的一位教授有麻烦
because I had overspent the department's
因为我超出了部门的范围
budget it's a different story but so I I
预算这是一个不同的故事，但所以我
actually wanted the efficient
实际上想要高效
implementation because I also wanted to
实施因为我也想
explore what would happen with a larger
探索更大的事情会发生什么
number of generations and a larger sort
世代数和更大的排序
of
的
size of the of the board and so once the
董事会的规模 等等
implementation was flawless I would feed
实施是完美的， 我会喂
at different patterns and then I think
在不同的模式 ，然后我想
maybe there was a follow-up article
也许有一篇后续文章
where there were patterns that that were
那里有模式
like gliders parents that repeated
像滑翔机父母那样重复
themselves after a number of generations
经过几代人的追求
but translated one or two positions to
但是将 一两个职位 翻译 成了
the right or up or something like that
在向右或向上或类似的东西
and there were I remember things like
而且我记得像这样的事情
glider guns well you can you can google
滑翔机枪你可以谷歌
Conway's Game of Life is still of people
康威的生命游戏仍然是人
still go on and over it
还是一遍又一遍
for a reason because it's not really
有一个原因，因为它不是真的
well understood why I mean this is what
很明白为什么我的意思是这是什么
Stephen Wolfram is obsessed about yeah
斯蒂芬沃尔夫勒姆痴迷于 耶
okay so he's just the the we don't have
好吧所以他只是我们没有的
the mathematical tools to describe the
描述的 数学工具
kind of complexity of the emerges in
那种 复杂的 出现在
these kinds of systems and the only way
这些系统和唯一的方法
to do is to run it I'm not convinced
要做的就是 运行 它我不相信
that that it's sort of a problem that
那是一个问题
lends itself to two classic mathematical
适合两个经典的数学
analysis no and so one one theory of how
分析没有，所以一个理论如何
you create an artificial intelligence or
你 创造了一个人工智能 或
artificial being is you kind of have to
人为 存在是你必须要的
send with a game of life you kind of
生活的游戏 给 你一种
have to create a universe and let it run
必须创建一个宇宙并让它运行
that creating it from scratch in a
从头开始创建它
design way in the you know coding up a
在你知道编码的设计方式
Python program that creates a full
创建完整的Python程序
intelligence system may be quite
情报系统可能相当
challenging that you might need to
具有挑战性的 ， 你可能需要
create a universe just like the game of
像 游戏 一样创造一个宇宙
life is
生活是
well you might have to experiment with a
好吧，你可能要试验一个
lot of different universes before there
很多不同的宇宙之前有
there is a set of rules that doesn't
有一套规则没有
essentially always just end up repeating
基本上总是最终重复
itself in in a trivial way yeah and
本身是 一种琐碎的方式耶和华
analyst Steve wolf from Stephen Wolfram
Stephen Wolfram的 分析师史蒂夫 狼
works with these simple rules says that
使用这些简单的规则说
it's kind of surprising how quickly find
如何快速找到它真是令人惊讶
rules that create interesting things you
创造有趣事物的规则
shouldn't be able to but somehow you do
不应该以某种方式你做
and so maybe our universe is laden with
也许我们的宇宙充满了
with rules that will create interesting
规则将创造 有趣的
things that might not look like humans
可能 看起来不像 人类的东西
but yeah you know emergent phenomena
但是，你知道紧急现象
that's interesting may not be as
有趣的可能不是那样
difficult to create as we think
很难 创建，因为我们认为
sure but let me sort of ask at that time
当然可以让我在那个时候问一下
you know some of the world's least in
你知道一些世界上最少的人
popular press was kind of captivated
大众媒体有点被迷住了
perhaps at least in America by the idea
或许至少在美国 这个想法
of artificial intelligence that that
人工智能那个
these computers would be able to think
这些电脑将 能够思考
pretty soon and yeah that touch you at
很快，是的， 触摸你
all did that in science fiction or in
所有这些都是在科幻小说中或在
reality in uh in anyway I didn't really
现实呃反正 我真的不
start reading science fiction until much
开始阅读科幻小说
much later
很久以后
I think as a teenager I I read maybe one
我认为，作为一个青少年，我 可能会读一个
bundle of science fiction stories was in
一堆科幻故事在
my background somewhere like in your
我的背景就像你的背景
thoughts that sort of the using
想法， 排序使用
computers to build something intelligent
计算机构建智能的东西
always fell to me because I had I felt I
总是 落到 我身边，因为我感觉到了我
had so much understanding of what
对什么有如此多的了解
actually goes on inside a computer I I
实际上是在电脑 II 里面
knew how many bits of memory it had and
知道它有多少内存和
how difficult it was to program and sort
编程和排序有多困难
of I didn't believe at all that that you
我根本不相信你
could just build something intelligent
可以建立一些聪明的东西
out of that that that would really sort
除此之外，那将 是真正的排序
of satisfy my definition of intelligence
满足我对智力的定义
I think the most the most influential
我认为 最有影响力的
thing that I read in my early 20s was
我在20岁出头读到的东西是
girlish ABBA that was about
少女ABBA即将到来
consciousness and that was a big
意识，这是一个很大的问题
eye-opener in in some sense in what
在 某种意义上让人大开眼界
sense oh so console yeah so on your own
感觉哦所以 控制台 是的，所以你 自己
brain did you do use did you at the time
你当时做过大脑吗？
or do you now see your own brain as a
或者你现在把自己的大脑视为一个
computer or is there a total separation
电脑还是完全分开的
of the way so yeah you're very
所以，是的，你是非常的
pragmatically practically know the
实际上实际上知道了
limits of memory the limits of this
记忆的极限是这个极限
sequential computing or weakly paralyzed
顺序计算或弱瘫痪
computing and you just know what we have
计算， 你只知道我们有什么
now and it's hard to see how it creates
现在， 很难看出它是如何创造的
but it's also easy to see it was in the
但它也很容易看到它是在
40s 50s 60s and now at least
40s 50s 60s 现在至少
similarities between the brain and our
大脑 和我们 之间的相似之处
computers oh yeah I mean I I totally
电脑哦，是的，我的意思是完全
believe that brains are computers in
相信大脑是计算机
some sense I mean the rules they they
某种意义上， 我指的是他们的规则
used to play by are pretty different
以前玩的很不一样
from the rules we we can sort of
从我们可以的规则
implement in in our current hardware but
在我们当前的 硬件中实现但是
I don't believe in like
我不相信
a separate thing that infuses us with
一个让我们注意的独立事物
intelligence or consciousness or any of
智力或意识或任何
that there's no soul I've been an
我 没有灵魂
atheist probably from when I was 10
无神论者可能从我10岁开始
years old just by thinking a bit about
只是思考 一下几岁
math and the universe and then well my
数学和宇宙， 然后我的
parents were atheists now I know that
父母是无神论者，现在我知道 ，
you you you could be an atheist and
你你你可能是一个无神论者 ，
still believe that there is something
仍然相信 有一些东西
sort of about intelligence or
关于情报或
consciousness that cannot possibly
意识不可能
emerge from a fixed set of rules I am
我是 从一套固定的规则中产生的
NOT in that camp
不在那个营地
I I totally see that sort of given how
我完全看到了那种 给定的方式
many millions of years evolution took
数百万年的进化花了
its time DNA is is a particular machine
它的时间DNA 是一种特殊的机器
that that sort of encodes information
这种 信息 编码
and an unlimited amount of information
和无限量的信息
in in chemical form and has figured out
在化学形式，已经找到了
a way to replicate itself I thought that
我想 是一种复制自己的方法
death was maybe it's 300 million years
死亡可能是3亿年
ago but I thought it was closer to half
以前，但 我认为 它接近 一半
a billion years ago that that's sort of
十亿年前 的那种情况
originated and it hasn't really changed
起源并没有真正改变
that the sort of the structure of DNA
那种 DNA 的结构
hasn't changed ever since that is like
从那以后就没有改变过
our binary code that you're having
那您在我们的二进制代码
hardware I mean the basic programming
硬件我指的是 基本编程
language hasn't changed but maybe the
语言没有改变， 但可能是
programming itself of has lead it did it
编程本身 已经导致它做到了
sort of it it happened to be a set of
它碰巧是一组
rules that was good enough to to sort of
足够 好的 规则
develop endless variability and and sort
发展无穷无尽的变化和排序
of the the idea of self-replicating
自我复制的想法
molecules competing with each other for
分子相互竞争
resources and and one type eventually
资源和最终的一种类型
sort of always taking over that happened
那种总是接管所发生
before there were any fossils so we
之前有化石，所以我们
don't know how that exactly happened
不知道究竟是怎么回事
but I believe it it's it's clear that
但我相信它是显而易见的
that did happen and can you comment on
确实发生了，你可以评论
consciousness and how you see it because
意识以及你如何看待它，因为
I think we'll talk about programming
我想我们会谈论编程
quite a bit we'll talk about you know
我们会谈论你知道的很多
intelligence connecting to programming
连接到编程的 智能
fundamentally but consciousness
从根本上说是意识
consciousness is this whole lot of other
意识就是其他很多
thing do you think about it often as a
你经常把它想象成一个
developer of a programming language and
编程语言的开发者和
and as a human those those are pretty
而作为一个人，那些是美丽的
sort of separate topics my sort of my
那种独立的主题我的那种 我
line of work working with programming
使用编程的工作线
does not involve anything that that goes
不涉及任何事情
in the direction of developing
在发展方向
intelligence or consciousness but sort
智力或意识，但排序
of privately as an avid reader of
私下作为狂热的读者
popular science writing I I have some
科普写作 我有一些
thoughts which which is mostly that I
这些想法主要是我
don't actually believe that
实际上并不相信
consciousness is an all-or-nothing thing
意识是一种全有或全无的东西
I have a feeling that and and I forget
我有一种感觉， 而且我忘记了
what I read that influenced this but I
我读到的东西影响了我，但我
feel that if you look at a cat or a dog
觉得如果你 看一只猫或一只狗
or a mouse they have some form of
或者他们有某种形式的老鼠
intelligence if you look at a fish it
智慧，如果你看一条鱼吧
has some form of intelligence and that
有某种形式的智慧和那种
evolution just took a long time but I
进化只是花了很长时间， 但我
feel that the the sort of the evolution
觉得 那种演变
of more and more intelligence that led
越来越多的情报 导致
to to sort of the human form of
以某种人的形式来分类
intelligence follow the evolution of the
情报跟随的演变
senses especially the visual sense I
特别感觉 我 的视觉感受
mean there is an enormous amount of
意味着有大量的
processing that's needed to interpret a
解释 a 所需的处理
scene and humans are still better at
场景和人类仍然更好
that than then computers
那比计算机
yeah and so and and and I have a feeling
是的，所以和我有一种感觉
that there is a sort of the reason that
有 一种 原因
that like mammals is in particular
像哺乳动物一样 特别
developed the levels of consciousness
提高了意识水平
that they have and that eventually read
他们拥有并 最终 阅读
sort of informative going from
从中获取信息
intelligence to to self-awareness in
智能自我意识
consciousness has to do with sort of
意识与某种意义 有关
being a robot that has very highly
是一个非常高的机器人
developed senses as a lot of rich
发展 出很多富有的 感官
sensory information coming in so the
感觉信息就这样了
it's a really interesting thought that
这是一个非常有趣的想法
the that whatever that basic mechanism
无论那个基本机制
of DNA
DNA 的
whatever that basic building blocks are
无论那些基本构件 是什么
programming is you if you just add more
如果你只是添加 更多，编程就是你
abilities more more high resolution
能力更高分辨率
sensors more sensors you just keep
传感器您只需保留更多传感器
stacking those things on top that
把那些东西叠在上面
there's basic programming in trying to
有 尝试 的基本编程
survive develops very interesting things
生存发展非常有趣的事情
that start to us humans to appear like
开始让我们人类 看起来像
intelligence and consciousness yeah so
智慧和意识是的
in in as far as robots go I think that
在尽可能机器人去我 认为 ，
the self-driving cars have the sort of
自动驾驶汽车有那种
the greatest opportunity of developing
发展的 最大机会
something like that
类似的东西
because when I Drive myself
因为我开车的时候
I don't just pay attention to the rules
我不只是要注意规则
of the road I also look around and I get
在路上我也环顾四周，我明白了
clues from that oh this is a shopping
从那个线索哦，这是一个购物
district oh here's an old lady crossing
区哦，这是一位老太太穿越
the street oh here is someone carrying a
街上哦，这里有人带着
pile of mail there's a mailbox thatthat
邮件堆有一个邮箱 thatthat
should they're gonna cross the street to
如果他们 要过马路 去
reach that mailbox and I slowed down and
到达那个邮箱，我放慢了速度
I don't even think about that yeah and
我甚至都没想过 是的
and so there is there's so much where
所以这里面就有这么多的 地方
you turn your observations into an
你把你的观察变成了一个
understanding of what utter
了解什么是彻头彻尾的
consciousnesses are going to do or what
意识是 要做什么或什么
what utter systems in the world are
什么在 世界上 绝对系统
going to be oh that tree is gone at
那棵树已经消失了
fault
故障
yeah I see sort of I see much more of
是的，我看到有点像我看到的更多
expect somehow that if anything is going
如果有什么事情 发生的 话，不知何故
to become conscious it's going to be the
要意识到 这将是
self-driving car and not the network of
自动驾驶汽车，而不是网络
a bazillion computers at in a Google or
谷歌或谷歌的数以亿计的计算机
Amazon data center that are all
所有的亚马逊数据中心
networked together to to do whatever
联网起来做任何事情
they do so in that sense so you actually
他们就是这样做的， 所以你真的
have like is that's what I work in
我 喜欢这就是我的工作
autonomous vehicles you highlight a big
自动驾驶汽车你突出了一个 大
gap between what we currently can't do
与我们 目前无法做到的差距
and what we truly need to be able to do
以及我们真正 需要做的事情
to solve the problem under that
解决下 这个问题
formulation and consciousness and
制定和意识
intelligence is something that basically
智力基本上是一种东西
a system should have in order to
一个系统 应该有
interact with us humans as opposed to
与我们人类互动而不是
some kind of abstract notion of a
某种抽象的概念
consciousness consciousness is something
意识意识是某种东西
that you need to have to be able to
你需要必须能够
empathize to be able to fear the
同情 能够害怕
understand what the fear of death is all
明白对死亡的恐惧是什么
these aspects that are important for
这些方面很重要
interaction with pedestrians you need to
与您需要的行人互动
be able to do basic computation based on
能够做基于的基本计算
our human desires and flaws sort of yeah
我们的人类欲望和瑕疵是的
if you if you look at the dog the dog
如果你看狗狗的话
clearly knows I mean I'm not the dog out
清楚地知道我的意思是我不是狗
on my brother I have friends who have
在我的兄弟， 我有朋友谁
dogs the dogs clearly know what the
狗狗清楚地知道了什么
humans around them are going to do or
他们周围的人会做或
the least they have a model of what
至少他们有什么样的模型
those humans are going to do and they
那些人类会做什么，他们
learn the dot some dogs know when you're
学习一些狗知道你 的时间 点
going out and they want to go out with
走出去， 他们 想一起出去
you they're sad when you leave them
当你离开他们时他们很伤心
alone they cry they're afraid because
他们独自哭泣他们害怕因为
they were mistreated when they were
他们受到了 虐待
younger we we don't assign sort of
年轻的我们不分配
consciousness to dogs or at least not
对狗的意识或至少不是
not all that much but I also don't think
不是那么多，但我也不 认为
they have none of that so I think it's
他们没有这个，所以我认为是
it's consciousness and intelligence are
它的意识和智慧
not all or nothing
不是全部或全部
the spectrum it's really interesting but
这个频谱非常有趣但是
in returning to programming languages
在返回编程语言
and the way we think about building
以及我们思考建设的方式
these kinds of things about building
这些关于建筑的事情
intelligence building consciousness
智力建设意识
building artificial beings I think one
建造人造生物我认为 一个
of the exciting ideas came in the 17th
令人兴奋的想法出现在17日
century and with liveness Hobbes decart
世纪与 活跃度 霍布斯decart
where there's this feeling that you can
哪里有这种感觉，你可以
convert all thought all reasoning all
转换所有思想所有的推理
the thing that we find very special in
我们觉得非常特别的东西
our brains you can convert all that into
我们的大脑你可以将所有这些转化为
logic you can formalize it form a
逻辑你可以形成 一个
reasoning and then once you formalize
推理然后一旦你正式化
everything all of knowledge and you can
一切都是知识， 你可以
just calculate and that's what we're
只是计算，这就是我们所做的
doing with our brains is we're
和 我们的大脑 一起做是我们的
calculating so there's this whole idea
计算所以有这个想法
that we that this is possible that this
我们认为这是可能的， 这
we're aware of the concept of pattern
我们意识到 模式的概念
matching in the sense that we are aware
在 我们 意识到 的意义上匹配
of it now add a sort of thought you they
它 现在增加一种思想，你 自己
they had discovered incredible bits of
他们发现了令人难以置信的一点点
mathematics like Newton's calculus and
数学如牛顿的微积分和
they're sort of idealism they're they're
这些人都有点理想主义的他们是他们
sort of extension of what they could do
他们可以 做 什么的扩展
with logic and math sort of went along
随着逻辑 和数学的变化
those lines and they thought there
那些线，他们想到了那里
there's like yeah logic there's there's
就像是的逻辑那里有
like a bunch of rules and a bunch of
像一堆规则和一堆
input they didn't realize that how you
输入他们没有 意识到你是怎么做的
recognize a face is not just a bunch of
认识到一张脸不仅仅是一堆
rules but it's a ton of data plus a
规则，但它是一大堆数据加上一个
circuit that that sort of interprets the
那种解释的电路
visual clues and the context and
视觉线索和背景和
everything else and somehow can
其他一切，不知何故 可以
massively parallel pattern match against
大规模并行模式匹配
stored rules I mean but if I see you
存储的规则我的意思是但如果我看到你
tomorrow here in front of the drop box
明天就在 投币箱前面
office I might recognize you even if I'm
办公室我可能会认出你， 即使我是
wearing a different shirt yeah but if I
穿着不同的衬衫是的，但如果我
if I see you tomorrow in a coffee shop
如果我明天在咖啡店见到你
in Belmont
在贝尔蒙特
I might have no idea
我可能不知道
that was you or on the beach or whatever
那是你或在沙滩上或其他什么
hey I make those mistakes myself all the
嘿，我 自己 犯 了 这些错误
time I see someone that I only know s
我看到有人，我才知道
like oh this person is a colleague of my
喜欢哦，这个人是 我 的同事
wife's yeah and then I see them at the
妻子是啊然后我看到了他们
movies and I didn't recognize them but
电影，我不 认识他们，但
do you see those you call it pattern
你看到那些你称之为模式的人吗？
matching do you see that rules is unable
您是否看到规则无法匹配？
to encode that to you you everything you
把这一切都编码给你
see all the pieces of information you
看到 信息的所有作品 ，你
look around this room I'm wearing a
看看这个房间我穿着
black shirt I have a certain height I'm
黑色衬衫我有 一定的身高我
a human all these you can there's
一个人，你可以在那里
probably tens of thousands of facts you
你可能有成千上万的事实
pick up moment by moment about this
关于这一点一点一点地接受
scene you take them for granted and you
你认为他们 是理所当然的 场景
accumulate aggregate them together to
积累聚集在一起
understand the scene
了解现场
you don't think all that could be
你不认为这一切都可能
encoded to where at the end of the day
编码到 一天结束时的位置
you can just put it all on the table and
你可以把它全部放在 桌子上
calculate oh I don't know what that
算哦，我 不知道那是什么
means I mean yes in the sense that there
意思是我的意思是在那里
is no there there is no actual magic
不 存在没有真正的魔法
there but there are enough layers of
有 ，但也有足够的层
abstraction from sort of from the facts
从事实中抽象出来
as they enter my eyes in my ears to the
当他们从我的耳朵 进入我的眼睛
understanding of the scene that that's I
了解那是我的场景
don't think that that AI has really
不要 以为AI确实存在
covered enough of of that distance it's
足够的距离覆盖了它
like if you take a human body and you
就像你带走了 人体一样
realize it's built out of atoms well
意识到它是由原子构建的
that that is a uselessly reductionist
那是一个无用的还原论者
view right right the body is built out
查看右侧身体已建立
of organs the organs are built out of
器官是由器官构成的
cells the cells are built out of
细胞是由细胞构成的
proteins the proteins are built out of
蛋白质是由蛋白质构成的
amino acids the amino acids are built
氨基酸是氨基酸的基础
out of atoms and then you get to quantum
在原子之外然后你得到 量子
mechanics so that's a very pragmatic
机械师这是一个 非常务实的
view I mean obviously is an engineer I
我的 意思是显然是一名工程师
agree with that kind of view but I also
同意这种观点，但我也同意
you also have to consider the the with
你还必须考虑到
the same harris view of well well
同样 哈里斯的 观点很好
intelligence is just information
情报就是信息
processing these just like you said you
就像你说的，你处理这些
take in sensory information you do some
记录你做的一些感官信息
stuff with it and
用它和它的东西
you come up with actions that are
你想出的 行动 是
intelligent that McGee makes it sound so
聪明的McGee让它听起来 如此
easy I don't know who Sam Harris is oh
很容易我不 知道Sam Harris是谁 哦
let's philosopher so like this how
让我们的哲学家如此喜欢
philosophers often think right and
哲学家经常思考正确和
essentially that's what the car was is
基本上这就是 汽车的意义所在
wait a minute if there is like you said
如果你说的话，请等一下
no magic
没有魔法
so you basically says it doesn't appear
所以你基本上说它没有出现
like there is any magic but we know so
就像有任何魔法， 但我们知道
little about it that it might as well be
它可能也是如此
magic so just because we know that we're
魔术只是因为我们知道 我们是
made of atoms just because we know we're
由原子组成仅仅是因为我们知道我们是
made of organs the fact that we know
由器官组成我们知道 的事实
very little hot to get from the atoms to
从原子到达的 热量很少
organs in a way that's recreate able
器官以一种可重建的方式
means it that you shouldn't get too
意味着你不应该太
excited just yet about the fact that you
对你这个事实感到很兴奋
figured out that we're made of atoms
我们 发现 我们是由原子组成的
right and and and the same about taking
关于服用的权利和相同
facts as are our sensory organs take
我们的感觉器官所 采取的 事实
them in and turning that into reasons
他们进入并将其 转化为 理由
and actions that sort of there are a lot
和那些有很多的行动
of abstractions that we haven't quite
我们还没有完成的抽象
figured out how to how to deal with
弄清楚如何 处理
those I mean I so sometimes I don't know
那些我的意思是我有时候我 不知道
if I can go on a tangent or not I
如果我 可以继续 切线 而不是 我
dragged you back in sure so if I take a
如果我拿一个，肯定会拖你回去
simple program that parses say say have
解析 说的 简单程序 说有
a compiler it parses a program in a
一个编译器，它解析一个程序
sense the input routine of that compiler
感知该编译器的输入例程
of that parser is a sense a sensing
该解析器的感觉是感知
Oregon and it builds up a mighty
俄勒冈州和它建立了一个强大的
complicated internal representation of
的复杂的内部表示
the program it just saw it doesn't just
它刚刚看到的程序不仅仅是
have a linear sequence of bytes
有一个线性的字节序列
representing the text of the program
代表程序的文本
anymore it has an abstract syntax tree
它有一个 抽象的语法树
and I don't know how many of your
我不知道你有多少人
viewers or listeners are familiar with
观众或听众都很熟悉
compiler technology but there's fewer
编译器技术但是更少
and fewer these days right that's also
这些日子也少了
true probably people want to take a
真的可能是人们想要一个
shortcut but they're sort of this
捷径， 但 他们就是这样
abstraction is a data structure that the
抽象是一种数据结构
compiler then uses to produce outputs
编译器然后用于产生输出
that is relevant like a translation of
这与翻译有关
the program to machine code that can be
机器代码的程序 可以
executed by by hardware and then the
由 硬件然后 执行
data structure gets thrown away when a
数据结构被丢弃 了
fish or a fly sees sort of gets visual
鱼或苍蝇看起来有点视觉
impulses I'm sure it also builds up some
冲动我相信它也会积累一些
data structure and for the fly that may
数据结构和可能的飞行
be very minimal a fly may may have only
一只苍蝇可能只有极少
a few I mean in the case of a fly's
我的意思 是飞行的一些
brain I could imagine that there are few
大脑我 可以想象 很少
enough layers of abstraction that it's
足够的抽象层
not much more than when it's darker here
没有什么比它在这里更黑暗的时候更多
than it is here well I can sense motion
比在这里我能感觉到运动
because a fly sort of responds when you
因为苍蝇会在你的时候做出反应
move your arm towards it so clearly it's
把你的手臂移向它，这是显而易见 的
visual processing is intelligent well
视觉处理非常智能
not intelligent but it has an
不聪明， 但它有一个
abstraction for motion and we still have
运动的抽象，我们仍然 有
similar things in in but much more
类似的东西，但更多
complicated in our brains I mean
我的意思是脑筋复杂
otherwise you couldn't drive a car if
否则你不能驾驶汽车，如果
you if you couldn't sort if you didn't
如果你没有，你就不能排序
have an incredibly good abstraction for
有一个令人难以置信的好抽象
motion yeah in some sense the same
运动是的，在某种意义上是一样的
abstraction for motion is probably one
动作的抽象可能是一个
of the primary sources of our of
我们的主要来源
information for us we just know what to
为我们提供的信息我们只知道该怎么 做
do I think we know what to do with that
我认为 我们知道该怎么做
we've built up other abstractions on top
我们在顶部建立了其他抽象
we've much more complicated data
我们有 更 复杂的数据
structures based on that and we build
基于这样的结构，我们 建立
more persistent data structures sort of
更持久的数据结构的 排序
after some processing some information
经过一些处理一些信息
sort of gets stored in our memory pretty
那种被存储在我们的记忆中 漂亮
much permanently and is available on
多和永久可以用
recall I mean there are some things that
回想一下， 我的意思是有 一些东西
you sort of you're conscious that you're
你有点意识到自己
remembering it like you give me your
记住它 就像你给我你的
phone number
电话号码
I well at my age I have to write it down
在我这个年纪，我必须把 它 写 下来
but I could imagine I could remember
但我可以想象我能记住
those seven numbers or 10 10 digits
那七个数字或10 个10位数
and reproduce them in a while if I sort
如果我排序，我会在一段时间内重现它们
of repeat them to myself a few times so
他们重复我自己几次 使
that's a fairly conscious form of
这是一种相当有意识的形式
memorization on the other hand how do I
记忆 另一方面我怎么做
recognize your face I have no idea my
认出你的脸， 我不知道 我的
brain has a whole bunch of specialized
大脑有一大堆专业
hardware that knows how to recognize
知道如何识别的硬件
faces I don't know how much of that is
面对我不知道有多少 是
sort of coded in our DNA and how much of
排序编码在我们的DNA， 以及如何 的 多
that is trained over and over between
被训练了个 遍之间
the ages of 0 and 3 but but but somehow
0 和3的年龄， 但但不知何故
our brains know how to do lots of things
我们的大脑知道如何做很多事情
like that that are useful in our
就像那些对 我们有用 的
interactions with with other humans with
与其他人的互动与
without really being conscious of how
没有真正意识到如何
it's done anymore right so where are
它已经完成了， 所以它 在哪里
actual d-day lives we're operating at
我们正在经营的实际d日生活
the very highest level of abstraction
最高级别的抽象
we're just not even conscious of all the
我们甚至 都 没有意识到 这一切
little details underlying it
它背后的细节
there's compilers on top of sec Turtles
在sec Turtles之上有编译器
on top of turtles or Turtles all the way
一直在海龟或 海龟之上
down it's compilers all the way down but
它的编译器一路向下但是
that's essentially you see that there's
基本上你看到的就是那个
no magic that's what I what I was trying
没有魔法就是我正在尝试的东西
to get at I think is with decart started
我认为是 开始的decart
this whole train of saying that there's
这整列火车 都说有
no magic I mean there's always before
没有魔法我的意思是总是以前
well then the cart also have the notion
那么购物车也 有这个概念
though that the soul and the body were
虽然灵魂和身体都是
were fundamentally separate yeah I think
从根本上说是分开的，我想是的
you had to write in God in there for
你必须 在那里 写上帝
political reasons so I don't actually
政治原因所以我实际上并没有
not historian but there's notions in
不是历史学家，而是历史学家
there that all of reasoning all of human
还有，所有的推理所有人类的
thought can be formalized I think that
思想可以正式化 我认为
continued in the 20th century with with
继续在20世纪 与
Russell and with with Gaydos
拉塞尔和盖多斯一起
incompleteness theorem this debate of
不完全性定理这一辩论
what what what are the limits of the
什么什么什么的极限
things that could be formalized that's
那些可以正式化的东西
where the touring machine came along and
旅游机出现的地方
this exciting idea I mean underlying a
这个令人兴奋的想法我的意思是潜
lot of computing that you can do quite a
你可以做 很多计算
lot with a computer you can you can
你可以 用 电脑很多
encode a lot of the stuff we're talking
编码我们正在谈论的很多东西
about in terms of recognizing faces and
在识别面孔方面
so on theoretically in an algorithm they
从理论上来说，算法就是他们的
can then run on a computer and in that
然后可以在计算机上，并运行
context I'd like to ask programming in a
上下文 我想问一下编程
philosophical way so what so what it
哲学的方式 那么 它 是 什么呢
what does it mean to program a computer
编程计算机意味着什么
so you said you write a Python program
所以你说你写了一个 Python程序
or a compiled a C++ program that
或编译的C ++程序
compiles to somebody code it's forming
编译成一个 正在形成的 代码
layers your your programming a layer of
将您的编程分层
abstraction is higher how do you see
抽象是更高你怎么看？
programming in that context can it keep
在这种情况下编程可以保持
getting higher and higher levels of
越来越高的水平
abstraction I think and at some point
抽象我认为 并且在某些时候
the higher level of levels of
更高水平的
abstraction will not be called
抽象不会被调用
programming and they will not resemble
编程，他们不会像
what we we call programming at the
我们称之为编程的是什么
moment there will not be source code I
那一刻不会有源代码我
mean there will still be source code
意味着仍然会有源代码
sort of at a lower level of the machine
在 机器的较低级别
just like they're still molecules and
就像他们仍然分子
electrons and and sort of proteins in
电子和各种蛋白质
our brains but and and so they're still
我们的大脑但是他们仍然如此
programming and and and system
编程和和系统
administration and who knows what's
管理，谁知道什么
keeping to keep the machine running but
保持机器运转但是
what the machine does is is a different
机器的作用是不同的
level of abstraction in a sense and as
从某种意义上说，抽象层次
far as I understand the way that for
据我了解的 那样
last decade or more people have made
过去的十年或更多的人 做出
progress with things like facial
面部护理等方面的进展
recognition or the self-driving cars is
认可 或自动驾驶汽车
all by endless endless amounts of
一切都是无穷无尽的
training data where at least as a
训练数据 至少作为 一个
layperson and I feel myself totally as a
外行， 我觉得自己完全是一个
layperson in that field
那个领域的外行
it looks like the researchers who
它看起来像研究人员
publish the results don't necessarily
公布结果不一定
know exactly how how their algorithms
确切知道他们的算法如何
work and that I often get upset when I
工作， 我经常生气 ，当 我
sort of read a sort of a fluff piece
有点读一种绒毛
about Facebook in the newspaper or
关于Facebook在报纸或
social networks and they say well Albert
社交网络，他们说好阿尔伯特
and that that's like a totally different
而这就像一个完全不同的
interpretation of the word algorithm
解释算法这个词
yeah because for me the way I was
是的，因为对我而言，就像我一样
trained or what I learned when I was
经过培训或者我学到了什么，当 我
eight or ten years old an algorithm is a
八，十年 的算法是一个
set of rules that you completely
设定的规则 ， 你完全
understand that can be mathematically
明白这可以是数学上的
analyzed and and and you can prove
分析 和，你可以证明
things you can like prove that Aires
你可以喜欢的东西证明了Aires
Dawson E's sieve produces all prime
Dawson E的 筛子产生所有素数
numbers and only prime numbers yes so I
数字，只有 素数 是的，所以我
don't know if you know how Andre
不知道如果你知道如何 安德烈
Carpathia's I'm afraid not
Carpathia， 我不敢
so he's a ahead of hey aya Tesla now but
所以他现在领先于嘿唉特斯拉，但是
his Stanford before and he has this
他以前是斯坦福大学，他有这个
cheeky way of calling this concept
厚脸皮的方式称这个概念
software 2.0 so let me disentangle that
软件2.0让我解开它
for a second so the so kind of what
一秒钟，所以那样的东西
you're referring to is the traditional
你指的是传统
traditional the the algorithm the
传统的算法
concept of an algo something that's
算法的概念是什么的
there is clear you can read it you
很清楚，你可以读到它
understand it you can prove its
明白你可以证明 它
functioning it's kind of software 1.0
运行它的 软件1.0
and what software 2.0 is is exactly what
什么软件2.0 正是如此
you described which is you have neural
你描述了哪个是神经的
networks which is a type of machine
网络是一种机器
learning that you feed a bunch of data
了解到 您提供了大量 数据
and that neural network learns to do a
并且 神经网络学会做一个
function all you specifies the inputs
函数所有你指定输入
and the outputs you want and you can't
和你想要 的 输出，你不能
look inside you can't analyze it all you
看看里面你无法分析 它
can do is train this function to map the
能做的就是训练 这个功能来映射
inputs the outputs by giving a lot of
通过提供很多来输入输出
data in that sense programming becomes
那种意义上的数据编程变成了
getting a lot of cleaning getting a lot
得到很多清洁工作得到 了很多
of data that's what programming is in
数据编程是什么
this well that would be programming 2.0
这很好，这将编程2.0
2.0 to programming 2.0 I I wouldn't call
2.0 到编程2.0 II不会打电话
that programming it's just a different
编程它只是一个不同的
activity just like building organs out
活动 就像建立器官一样
of cells is not called chemistry well so
细胞的化学性质并不好
let's just set that back and think sort
让我们回过头来 思考排序
of more generally of course but you know
当然 更普遍 ， 但你知道
it's like as a parent teaching teaching
就像父母 教学一样
your kids things can be called
你孩子的事情可以召唤
programming in that same sense that
以同样的意义编程
that's
那是
how program has been used you're
你是如何使用程序的
providing them data examples use cases
为他们提供数据示例用例
so imagine writing a function not by not
所以 想象一下 写一个函数 不是没有
with for loops and clearly readable text
带有for循环和清晰 可读的文本
but more saying well here's a lot of
但更多的说得好，这里有很多
examples of what this function should
这个函数 应该 是什么的例子
take and here's a lot of examples when
走在这里的很多例子 ，当
it takes those functions it should do
它需要它应该做的那些功能
this and then figure out the rest so
这个，然后弄清楚其余的
that's the 2.0 concept and the this is
这是2.0概念，而这是
the question I have for you is like it's
我给 你的问题就是它
a very fuzzy way this is a reality of a
一个很模糊的方式，这是一个现实
lot of these pattern recognition systems
很多这些模式识别系统
and so on
等等
it's a fuzzy way of quote-unquote
这是一种模糊的报价方式 - 不引用
programming what do you think about this
编程你怎么看待这个
kind of world it should be called
什么样 的世界它应该 被称为
something totally different than
完全不同的东西
programming it's like if you're a
编程它 就像你是一个
software engineer does that mean you're
软件工程师这意味着你是谁
you're designing systems that are very
你正在设计非常好的系统
can be systematically tested evaluated
可以进行系统的测试评估
they have a very specific specification
他们有一个非常具体的规范
and then this other fuzzy software 2.0
然后是其他模糊软件2.0
world machine learning world that's
世界机器学习世界这
that's something else totally or is
那是完全或者完全不同的东西
there some intermixing that it's
那里有一些混合
possible well the question is probably
很可能这个问题很可能
only being asked because we we don't
只是被问到，因为我们没有
quite know what that software 2.0
很清楚 那个 软件2.0 是 什么
actually is and it sort of I think there
实际上是，我认为那里
is a truism that every task that AI has
人工智能所具有的每项任务都是不言而喻的
has tackled in the past at some point we
在某些时候我们已经解决过了
realized how it was done and then it was
意识到它是如何完成的然后它是
no longer considered part of artificial
不再 被视为 人工的一部分
intelligence because it was no longer
情报，因为它不再存在
necessary to to use that term it was
有必要使用这个术语
just oh now he we know how to do this
哦，现在他知道怎么做了
and a new field of science or
和一个新的科学领域
engineering has been developed and I
工程已经开发和我
don't know if sort of every form of
不知道是否各种形式
learning or
学习或
sort of controlling computer systems
一种控制计算机系统
should always be called programming I
应始终称为编程我
said I that I don't know maybe I'm
我说我不知道​​也许我是
focused too much on the terminology i
过分关注术语我
but i expect that that there just will
但我想到的是， 有刚会
be different concepts where people with
与人有不同的概念
sort of different education and a
一种不同的教育和
different model of what they're trying
他们正在尝试的不同模式
to do will will develop those concepts
将要做的将发展这些概念
yeah and i guess if you could comment
是的， 我想如果你能发表评论
and another way to put this concept is i
另一种说明这个概念的方法是 我
think i think the kind of functions that
我认为我认为 那种功能
neural networks provide is things as
神经网络提供的东西就像
opposed to being able to upfront prove
反对能够提前 证明
that this should work for all cases you
这适用于所有情况
throw at it all you're able it's the
扔掉它所有你能够做到的
worst case analysis versus average case
最坏情况分析与 平均情况
analysis all you're able to say is it's
分析所有你能 说的是它的
it seems on everything we've tested to
它似乎在我们测试过的所有内容上
work 99.9 percent of the time but we
99.9％的时间工作，但我们
can't guarantee it and it it fails in
不能保证它，它失败 了
unexpected ways but can't even give you
意想不到的方式， 但甚至不能给你
examples of how it fails in unexpected
如何在意外情况下失败的例子
ways but it's like really good most of
方式， 但它是非常 好的 大多数
the time yeah but there's no room for
是的 时间，但没有空间
that in current ways we think about
以我们现在的方式思考
programming programming 1.0 is actually
编程编程1.0 实际上是
sort of getting to that point to where
那种让该 点的地方
the sort of the ideal of a bug-free
那种一个 无缺陷 的理想
program has been abandoned long ago by
程序早已被废弃了
most software developers we only care
大多数软件开发者我们只关心
about bugs that manifest themselves
关于表现自己的错误
often enough to be annoying and we're
经常足以 让我们烦恼
willing to take the occasional crash or
愿意偶尔崩溃或
outage or incorrect result for granted
停电或错误的结果是理所当然的
because we can't possibly we don't have
因为我们不可能没有
enough programmers to make all the code
足够的程序员来制作所有代码
bug free and it would be an
没有错误，它将是一个
credibly tedious business and if you try
可靠的乏味业务，如果你尝试
to throw formal methods at it it gets it
抛出正式方法就可以了
becomes even more tedious so every once
每一次变得更加乏味
in a while the user clicks on a link in
用户在一段时间内点击 了链接
and somehow they get an error and the
并以某种方式他们得到一个错误和
average user doesn't panic they just
普通用户不会对他们感到恐慌
click again and see if it works better
再次单击， 看看它是否更好
the second time which often magically it
第二次，这通常是神奇的
does or they go up and they try some
是或他们上升 ， 他们尝试一些
other way of performing their tasks so
其他方式执行 他们的任务
that's sort of an end-to-end recovery
那是一种 端到端的 复苏
mechanism and inside systems there is
机制和内部系统有
all sorts of retries and timeouts and
各种重试和超时 和
fall backs and I imagine that that sort
倒退，我想那样
of biological systems are even more full
生物系统 更加充实
of that because otherwise they wouldn't
因为否则他们不会
survive do you think programming should
生存你认为编程应该
be taught and thought of as exactly what
被教导和思考正是如此
you just said before I come from is kind
在 我来 之前你刚才 说的 是善良的
of you're almost denying that fact
的 你几乎否认这一事实
always in the insert of basic
总是插入 基本的
programming education the sort of the
编程教育的那种
program's you're you're having students
程序 是你在学生
right are so small and simple that if
权利是如此小而简单，如果
there is a bug you can always find it
你总能找到一个bug
and fix it because the sort of
并修复它，因为 那种
programming as it's being taught in some
编程，因为它正在教授一些
even elementary middle schools in high
甚至高中的初中
school introduction to programming
学校介绍编程
classes in college typically it's
大学里的课程通常是这样的
programming in the small very few
在极少数人中编程
classes sort of actually teach software
类实际上教软件
engineering building large systems I
工程建设大系统我
mean every summer here at Dropbox we
这意味着每年夏天我们都会在Dropbox
have a large number of interns every
每个人都有大量的实习生
tech company on the west coast has the
西海岸的科技公司有
same thing these interns are always
同样的事情这些实习生总是如此
amazed because this is the first time in
惊讶， 因为这是第一次
their life
他们的 生活
that they see what goes on in a really
他们看到真的发生了什么
large software development environment
大型软件开发环境
and everything they've learned in
以及他们所学到的一切
college was almost always about a much
大学 几乎总是有很多
smaller scale and somehow the difference
较小的规模和某种程度上 的差异
in scale
在规模
makes a qualitative difference in how
如何产生质的差异
you how you do things and how you think
你是如何做事以及如何 思考的
about it if you then take a few steps
关于它，如果你再 采取 一些步骤
back in two decades seventies and
回到二十 年代 和 七十年代
eighties when you're first thinking
八十年代， 当 你第一次思考
about Python or just that world of
关于Python或只是那个世界
programming languages did you ever think
您是否曾想过 编程语言 ？
that there would be systems as large as
会有像这样大的系统
underlying Google Facebook and Dropbox
基础Google Facebook和Dropbox
did you when you were thinking about
你什么时候 你 想
Python I was actually always caught by
Python我其实总是被抓住
surprise by
惊讶的是
yeah pretty much every stage of
是的，几乎每个阶段
computing so maybe just because uh you
计算所以也许只是因为你
spoken in other interviews but I think
在其他采访中说，但我认为
the evolution of programming languages
编程语言的演变
are fascinating it's especially because
令人着迷的特别是因为
it leads from my perspective towards
它从我的观点走向了
greater and greater degrees of
越来越大的程度
intelligence
情报
I learned the first programming language
我学会了第一种编程语言
I played with in in Russia was with the
我在 俄罗斯和 我一起玩过
turtle logo logo yeah and if you look I
乌龟标志标志是啊如果你看我
just have a list of programming
只是有一个编程列表
languages all of which I've known played
所有我熟悉过的语言
with a little bit and they're all
一点点，他们都是
beautiful in different ways from Fortran
从Fortran以不同的方式美丽
COBOL Lisp Algol 60 basic logo and C as
COBOL Lisp Algol 60基本标志和C as
a few the object-oriented came along in
一些面向对象出现了
the 60s Simula Pascal small talk all of
60年代 Simula Pascal的小谈话全部
that lean all the classics the classics
将 所有 经典 都 倾注于经典之作
yeah the classic hits write scheme built
是的经典命中写计划 建立
that's built on top of Lisp on the
这是建立在Lisp 之上的
database side SQL C++ and all that leads
数据库端SQL C ++以及所有这些
up to Python Pascal - and that's before
Python Pascal  - 之前就是这样
Python MATLAB these kind of different
Python MATLAB 这些不同
communities different languages so he
社区 不同语言 所以他
talked about that world I know that
谈到那个我知道的世界
Python came out of ABC which actually
Python实际上来自ABC
never knew that language I just having
从来不知道 我 只是有 那种语言
researched this conversation went back
研究这个对话回去了
to ABC and it looks remarkably it it has
到ABC，看起来非常棒
a lot of annoying qualities but
很多讨厌的品质 但是
underneath those like all caps and so on
在像所有帽子之类的东西下面等等
but underneath that there's elements of
但在其下面 有元素
Python that are quite if they're already
Python中 是相当 ，如果 他们已经
there that's where I got all the good
在那里，我得到了所有的好处
stuff
东西
all the good stuff so but in that world
所有好东西，但在那个世界
you're swimming these programming
你正在游泳这些节目
languages were you focused on just the
语言是你只关注了
good stuff in your specific circle but
你 特定圈子里的 好东西 但是
did you have a sense of what what is
你有什么感觉吗？
everyone chasing you said that every
每个人都在追逐你
programming language is built to scratch
编程语言是为了划痕而构建的
an itch mm-hmm
痒mm-hmm
were you aware of all the itches in the
你是否意识到了所有的痒
community and if not or if yes I mean
社区，如果没有，或者如果是，我的意思是
what H we trying to scratch with Python
我们试图用Python划伤的是什么
well I'm glad I wasn't aware of all the
好吧，我很高兴我不知道所有的
itches because I would probably not have
发痒，因为我可能没有
been able to do anything I mean if
能够做任何我的意思， 如果
you're trying to solve every problem at
你正试图 解决每一个问题
once you saw nothing well yeah that it's
一旦你没有看到任何东西 ，那就是它
it's too overwhelming and so I had a
它太喧宾夺主， 所以我有一个
very very focused problem I wanted a
非常非常集中的问题，我想要一个
programming language that set somewhere
设置在某处的编程语言
in between shell scripting and C and now
在shell脚本和C之间以及现在
arguably there is like one is higher
可以说有一个更高
level one is lower level and Python is
第一级是较低级别， Python是
sort of a language of an intermediate
一种中间语言
level although it's still pretty much at
水平，虽然 它仍然 很多
the high level and no I was I was
高水平，我不是
thinking about much more about I want a
想更多关于我想要一个
tool that I can use to be more
工具， 我可以 用 更
productive as a programmer in a very
作为程序员 在一个非常有效的
specific environment and I also had
特定的环境，我也有
given myself a time budget for the
给自己一个时间预算
development of the tool and that was
这个工具的开发就是这样
sort of about three months for both the
两个人大约三个月
design like thinking through
设计就像思考
what are all the features of the
是什么的所有功能
language syntactically and semantically
语法和语义
and how do i implement the whole
以及我如何实现整体
pipeline from parsing the source code to
从解析源代码到的管道
executing it so I think both were the
执行它所以我认为两者都是
timeline and the goals it seems like
时间表和目标 似乎
productivity was at the core of it as a
生产力是它的核心
goal so like for me in the 90s and the
这个目标在90年代就和我一样
first decade of the 21st century I was
我是 21 世纪的第一个十年
always doing machine learning AI
总是做机器学习AI
programming for my research was always
总是为我的研究编程
in C++ and then and then the other
在C ++ 然后然后另一个
people who are a little more mechanical
那些机械性更强的人
engineering Electrical Engineering our
工程电气工程我们的
MATLAB II they're a little bit more
MATLAB II 他们更多一点
MATLAB focus those are the world and
MATLAB专注于那些世界和
maybe a little bit Java too but people
也许有点 太多 的Java， 但人们
who are more interested in and
谁更感兴趣 和
emphasizing the object oriented nature
强调面向对象的本质
of things so but then in last 10 years
事情，但在 过去10年
or so especially with a calming of
或者特别是平静的
neural networks and these packages are
神经网络和这些包是
built on Python to interface with with
构建在Python 上与之交互
neural networks I switch to Python and
神经网络我切换到Python和
it's just I've noticed a significant
只是我注意到一个重要的
boost that I can't exactly because I
提升我不能完全因为我
don't think about it but I can't exactly
不要去想 它 ，但 我不能确切地
put into words why I'm just except much
说实话 为什么我 只是 除了很多
much more productive just being able to
能够更有效率
get the job done much much faster so how
如何更快地完成工作
do you think whatever that qualitative
你觉得那个定性的东西吗？
difference is I don't know if it's
不同的是，我不知道 这 是否 是
quantitative it could be just a feeling
量化它可能只是一种感觉
I don't know if I'm actually more
我不知道我是否真的更多
productive but how do you think about
有效但你怎么 想
Layar yeah well that that's right I
Layah 是的，那是对的
think there's elements let me just speak
认为有些元素 让 我说话
to one aspect that I think those affect
在一个 方面，我认为这些影响
that productivity is C++ was I really
生产力是 C ++，我真的
enjoyed creating performant code and
喜欢创建高性能的代码和
creating a beautiful structure where
创造一个美丽的结构， 其中
everything that you know this kind of
你知道的 一切
going into this especially with the
进入这个特别是与
newer newer standards of templated
更新的模板标准
programming of just really creating this
真正创造这个的编程
beautiful formal structure that I found
我找到了美丽的正式结构
myself spending most of my time doing
我大部分时间都在做
that as opposed to get
而不是得到
you parsing a file and extracting a few
你 解析文件，并提取了几
key words or whatever the task was
关键词或任务 是 什么
trying to do so what is it about Python
试图这样做是什么关于Python
how do you think of productivity in
您如何看待生产力？
general as you were designing it now
一般为你设计 ，现在 它
sort of through the decades last three
那种通过 过去三 十年来的
decades what do you think it means to be
几十年你认为它意味着什么
a productive programmer and how did you
一个富有成效的程序员，你是怎么做的
try to design it into the language there
尝试将其设计成那里的语言
are different tasks and as a programmer
是不同的任务和程序员
it's it's useful to have different tools
拥有不同的工具是有用的
available that sort of are suitable for
可用的排序的适合于
different tasks so I still write C code
不同的任务，所以我仍然写C代码
I still write shellcode but I write most
我仍然写shellcode但我写得最多
of my things in Python why do I still
我的东西在Python中为什么我 仍然
use those other languages because
使用那些其他语言，因为
sometimes the task just demands it and
有时任务只是要求它，
well I would say most of the time the
好吧，我会说大部分 时间
task actually demands a certain language
任务实际上需要某种 语言
because the task is not write a program
因为任务不是写程序
that solves problem x from scratch but
从头开始 解决 问题 x但是
it's more like fix bug in existing
它更像是现有的修复bug
program X or add a small feature to an
程序X或添加一个小功能
existing large program but even if if
现有的大型计划，但即使如果
you sort of if you're not constrained in
如果你没有 受到约束， 你会有点兴奋
your choice of language by context like
您可以通过上下文选择语言
that there is still the fact that if you
如果你 ， 还有一个事实
write it in a certain language then you
用你的 某种语言写它
sort of you you have this balance
你有这种 平衡 吗？
between how long does it time does it
间多久时间做它
take you to write the code and how long
带你写代码和 多长时间
does the code run and when you're in
代码是否运行以及何时进入
sort of in the face of exploring
那种在 探索的脸
solutions you often spend much more time
您经常花费更多时间的解决方案
writing the code than running it because
编写代码而不是运行它，因为
every time you've sort of you've run it
每当你有点运行它
you see that the output is not quite
你看到输出 是 不是很
what you wanted and you spend some more
你 想要什么， 你花了更多
time Cody
时间科迪
and a language like Python just makes
和像Python这样的语言
death iteration much faster because
死亡迭代更快，因为
there are fewer details there is a large
细节较少 有很多
library sort of there are fewer details
图书馆排序 的 细节 较少
that that you have to get right before
那你有权利 之前 得到
your program compiles and runs there are
你的程序编译和运行 有
libraries that do all sorts of stuff for
为 各种各样的东西做的图书馆
you so you can sort of very quickly take
这样你就可以 那种很迅速采取
a bunch of existing components put them
一堆现有的组件放了它们
together and get your prototype
一起来获取你的原型
application running just like when I was
应用程序运行就像我一样
building electronics I was using a
建筑电子我正在使用
breadboard most of the time so I had
线路板的大部分时间，所以我不得不
this like sprawl out circuit that if you
如果你这就像蔓延电路一样
shook it it would stop working because
震惊它会停止工作， 因为
it was not put together very well but it
它没有很好地组合在一起 但是它
functioned and all I wanted was to see
运作和 所有我想要 的 是 看
that it worked and then move on to the
它的工作， 然后移动到
next next schematic or design or add
接下来的原理图或设计或添加
something to it once you've sort of
一旦你有所作为的东西
figured out oh this is the perfect
想通了哦这是 完美的
design for my radio or light sensor or
设计为 我的无线电或光传感器或
whatever then you can say okay how do we
无论如何你可以说好吗我们怎么样
design a PCB for this how do we solder
设计一个PCB，我们如何焊接
the components in a small space how do
如何在小空间中 组件
we make it so that it is robust against
我们这样做是为了它坚固耐用
say voltage fluctuations or mechanical
说电压波动或 机械
disruption I mean I know nothing about
中断我的意思是 我什么都不知道
that when it comes to designing
在设计方面
electronics but I know a lot about that
电子产品，但我知道很多
when it comes to to writing code so the
当谈到 编写 代码所以
initial initial steps are efficient fast
初始初始步骤快速有效
and there's not much stuff that gets in
并没有太多的东西进入
the way but you're kind of describing
方式， 但 你有点描述
from a like Darwin described the
从像达尔文这样的描述中
evolution of species right you're you're
物种的进化权利，你就是你
observing of what is about true about
观察什么是真实的
Python now if you take step back if the
Python现在如果你采取后退，如果
art of if the act of creating languages
如果创造语言的行为的 艺术
is art and you had three months to do it
是艺术 ，你有三个月的 时间 去做
and initial steps and ha so you just
和初步的步骤，所以你只是
specified a bunch of goals sort of
指定排序 的一串目标
things that you observe about Python
的事情， 你观察到的Python
perhaps you had those goals but how do
也许你有这些目标但是怎么做
you create the rules the syntactic
你创建句法规则
structure the the features that result
结构 导致 的特征
in those so I have in the beginning and
这些让我在开始和
I have follow-up questions about through
我有关于通过的 后续 问题
the evolution of Python 2 but in the
Python 2的演变， 但在
very beginning when you're sitting there
当你坐在那里时就 开始了
creating the lexical analyzers or
创建词法 分析器或
whatever evolution was still a big part
无论进化如何仍然是重要的
of it because I I sort of I said to
它因为 我说的 那种
myself I don't want to have to design
我自己也不想 设计
everything from scratch I'm going to
一切从头开始我要去
borrow features from other languages
借用其他语言的功能
that I like Oh interesting so you
我喜欢哦有趣 所以你
basically exactly you first observe what
基本上你首先要 观察到什么
you like yeah and so that's why if
你喜欢是的，所以这就是为什么
you're 17 years old and you want to sort
你17岁了，你想排序
of create a programming language you're
创建一种编程语言
not going to be very successful at it
不会 很成功
because you have no experience with
因为你没有经验
other languages whereas I was in my
其他语言， 而我在我的
let's say mid-30s I had written parsers
让我们说30年代中期 我写过解析器
before so I had worked on the
之前，所以我就在工作
implementation of ABC I had spent years
我花了多年时间实施ABC
debating the design of ABC with its
用它的辩论来讨论ABC的设计
authors its with its designers I had
作者它 与它 的 设计师我有
nothing to do with the design it was
与它 的 设计无关
designed fully as it was ended up being
完全设计，因为它最终成为
implemented when I joined the team but
当我加入团队时实施但是
so you borrow ideas and concepts and
所以你借用了想法和概念
very concrete sort of local rules from
非常具体的地方规则来自
different languages like the indentation
不同的语言， 如缩进
and certain other syntactic features
和某些其他句法特征
from ABC but I chose to borrow string
来自ABC，但我选择借用字符串
literals and how numbers work from C and
文字和数字如何从C和
various other things so in then if you
如果你，那么其他各种各样的事情
take that further so yet you've had this
更进一步，所以 你已经有了这个
funny sounding but I think surprisingly
有趣的听起来，但我想惊讶
accurate and or at least practical title
准确的， 或至少是实用的 标题
of a benevolent dictator for life for
一个仁慈的独裁者为生命
quite you know for last three decades
你知道三十年了吗？
whatever or no not the actual title but
无论是否实际的标题，但是
functionally speaking so you had to make
从功能上说，你必须做
decisions design decisions can you maybe
你可能决定设计决定
let's take Python - there's a Python
让我们来看看Python  - 有一个Python
releasing Python 3 as an example mm-hmm
发布Python 3作为示例mm-hmm
it's not backward-compatible - Python -
它不向后兼容 - Python  -
in ways that a lot of people know so
以很多 人都知道的方式
what was that deliberation discussion
什么是审议讨论
decision like we have what was the
决定我们有什么是
psychology of that experience
那种 经历的心理学
do you regret any aspects of how that
你对这方面的任何方面感到遗憾吗？
experiments undergone that else yeah so
实验经历了其他的事情
it was a group process really it at that
这是一组进程真的在这一点
point even though I was be DFL in nine a
即使我 在 九岁 时 成为DFL
name and and certainly everybody sort of
名字，而且当然每个人都有
respected my my position as the creator
尊重我作为创作者的地位
and and the current sort of owner of the
和当前的所有者
language design I was looking at
我正在看的语言设计
everyone else for feedback sort of
其他人的反馈排序
Python 300 in some sense was sparked by
Python 300在某种意义上被引发 了
other people in the community pointing
社区中的其他人指点
out oh well there are a few issues that
出来 哦有几个 问题是
sort of bite users over and over can we
那种咬用户一遍又一遍，才能
do something about that and for Python
为此 做点什么， 为Python 做点什么
three we took a number of those Python
三，我们采取了一些 Python
wards as they were called at the time
他们当时被召唤的病房
and we said can we try to sort of make
我们说 我们可以尝试那种 使
small changes to the language that
对语言的微小改动
address those warts and we had sort of
解决那些疣，我们有点
in the past we had always taken
在过去我们一直采取
backwards compatibility very seriously
向后兼容性非常严重
and so many Python warts in earlier
以前有很多Python疣
versions had already been resolved
版本已经解决
because they could be resolved while
因为他们可以解决
maintaining backwards compatibility or
保持向后兼容性或
sort of using a very gradual path of
有点使用非常渐进的路径
evolution of the language in a certain
在一定 的 语言的演变
area and so we were stuck with a number
区域，所以 我们被困在 一个数字
of warts that were
这是疣
widely recognized as problems not like
被广泛认为是不一样的问题
road blocks but nevertheless sort of
路障，但仍然有点
things that some people trip over and
有些人绊倒的事情
you know that that's always the same
你知道那总是一样的
thing that that people trip over when
人们绊倒的事情
they trip and we could not think of a
他们旅行，我们想不到一个
backwards compatible way of resolving
向后兼容的解决方式
those issues but it's still an option to
这些问题，但它仍然是一个选项
not resolve the issues and so yes for
没有解决 问题，所以是的
for a long time we had sort of resigned
很长一段时间我们都有点辞职了
ourselves to well okay the language is
我们自己也 很好用这种语言
not going to be perfect in this way and
不会以 这种方式 完美
that way that way and we sort of certain
那种方式，我们有点确定
of these I mean there are still plenty
其中我的意思是 还有很多
of things where you can say well that's
的 事情，你可以说清楚的
that particular detail is better in Java
Java中的特定细节更好
or in R or in Visual Basic or whatever
或者在R 或Visual Basic或其他任何地方
and we're okay with that because well we
我们对此很好，因为 我们
can't easily change it it's not too bad
不能轻易改变它不是太糟糕
we can do a little bit with user
我们可以做 用户一点点
education or we can have a static
教育或我们 可以有一个静态
analyzer or warnings in in the parser or
解析器中的分析器 或 警告
something
某物
but there were things where we thought
但有些事情我们在想
well these are really problems that are
这些都是真正的问题
not going away they are getting worse in
不会离开 他们 会变得更糟
the future we should do something about
未来我们应该 做些 什么
do something but ultimately there is a
做一些事， 但最终有一个
decision to be made right yes so was
做出 正确的决定是的
that the toughest decision in the
这是最艰难的决定
history of Python yet to make as the
Python的历史还没有 作为
benevolent dictator for life or if not
仁慈的独裁者，如果 没有
what are there maybe even on a smaller
有什么可能甚至在较小的
scale what was a decision where you were
衡量你所处的决定
really torn up about well the toughest
真的是最艰难的
decision was probably to resign all
决定很可能辞职的所有
right let's go there hold on a second
正确的，让我们去那里等一下
then let me just because in the interest
然后让我只因为 感兴趣
of time too because I have a few cool
时间 也因为我有一些很酷
questions for you I let's touch a really
给你的问题我真的很感动
important one because it was quite
重要的一个， 因为它是相当的
dramatic and beautiful in certain kinds
在某些类型中戏剧性和美丽
of ways then in July this year three
然后在 今年7月的三个方式
months ago you wrote now that pepp 572
几个月前你 现在写了pepp 572
is done I don't ever want to have to
已经完成了我不想要的
fight so hard for a
为了这么努力而战
and find that so many people despise my
并发现有这么多人鄙视我的
decisions I would like to remove myself
决定我想 删除自己
entirely from the decision process I'll
完全来自 我的决策过程
still be there for a while as an
仍然存在 一段时间 作为一个
ordinary core developer and I'll still
普通的核心开发者 ，我还是会的
be available to mentor people possibly
提供给 可能 指导人
more available but I'm basically giving
更多可用，但我基本上 给予
myself a permanent vacation for being be
我自己永远度假
DFL yeah but not well in dictator for
DFL是啊但是 在独裁者中表现不佳
life and you all will be on your own
生活，你们都 将 靠 自己
it's just this it's a it's almost
就是这就是它的差不多了
Shakespearean I'm not going to appoint a
莎士比亚我不打算任命一个
successor so water you're all going to
继承人如此水，你们都会去
do create a democracy anarchy a
创造民主无政府状态a
dictatorship a federation so that was a
独裁统治一个联邦，所以这是一个
very dramatic and beautiful set of
非常戏剧性和美丽的一套
statements it's almost it's open-ended
声明它几乎是开放式的
nature called the community to create a
大自然叫社区创造了一个
future for Python this is kind of a
Python的未来这是一种
beautiful aspect to it well so what end
它的美丽方面 很好，所以结束了
and dramatic you know what was making
而戏剧性的你知道是在做什么
that decision like what was on your
那个决定就像 你的一样
heart on your mind stepping back now a
在你的头脑心脏现在退一步
few months later we could take you to
几个月后，我们可以带你去
your Maya thing I'm glad you liked of
您的 玛雅的事，我很高兴你喜欢的
writing because it was actually written
写作， 因为它实际上是写的
pretty quickly
很快
it was literally something like after
它实际上就像之后的事情
months and months of going around in
几个月到几个月的时间
circles I had finally approved Pet 572
圈子我终于批准了宠物572
which I had a big hand in its design
我在设计上占了上风
although it I didn't initiate it
虽然我没有发起 它
originally I gave it a bunch of nudges
最初我给了它一堆 推动
in a direction that would be better for
在一个方向，这将 是更好的
the language so I just asked it's a sink
语言，所以我只是问 它是一个下沉
I oh no the one or no no kept 572 was
我哦，没有一个或没有没有 保持572是
actually a small feature which is
实际上是一个小功能
assignment expressions assignment
赋值表达式赋值
expressions
表达式
dad had been taught there was just a lot
爸爸被教过那里有很多
of debate where a lot of people claimed
许多人声称 的 辩论
that they knew what was pythonic and
他们知道什么是pythonic和
what was not pythonic and
什么不是pythonic和
they knew that this was going to destroy
他们知道这会 破坏
the language this was like a violation
这种语言就像违规一样
of pythons most fundamental design
蟒蛇最基本的设计
philosophy and I thought that was all
哲学，我认为这就是全部
because I was in favor of it
废话，因为我赞成它
and that I would think I know something
并且我认为我知道一些事情
about pythons design philosophy so I was
关于蟒蛇的设计哲学，所以我是
really tired and also stressed of that
真的很累，也很强调
thing and literally after sort of
的事情，从字面上后排序
announcing I was going to accept it a
宣布我要接受它
certain Wednesday evening I had finally
某某星期三晚上我 终于来了
send the email it's accepted now let's
发送它现在接受的电子邮件让我们
just go implement it so I went to bed
只是去实施它所以我去 睡觉了
feeling really relieved that's behind me
感觉真的松了一口气 在我身后
and I wake up Thursday morning 7:00 a.m.
我星期四 早上7点起床
and I think well that was the last one
我认为 这是最后一个
that's going to be such such a terrible
那将 是 如此可怕
debate and that's it going to be said
辩论， 这是可以说的
that's the last time that I let myself
这是我 最后一次 让自己
be so stressed out about a peb decision
如此强调一个人的决定
I should just resign I've been sort of
我应该辞职，我一直都是
thinking about retirement for half a
考虑退休 半个月
decade I've been joking and sort of
十年来我一直在开玩笑 和排序
mentioning retirement sort of telling
提到退休的说法
the community some point in the future
社区 在 未来的 某些方面
I'm going to retire don't take that FL
我要退休了不要拿那个FL
part of my title too literally and I
我的标题的一部分太字面上和我
thought okay this is it I'm done I had
我想， 这就是我做完了
the day off I wanted to have a good time
休息日， 我想玩得开心
with my wife we were going to a little
和我的妻子， 我们要去一点点
beach town nearby and in he think maybe
附近的海滩小镇，他认为也许
15-20 minutes
15-20分钟
I wrote that thing that you just called
我写了你 刚才打过的 那个东西
Shakespearean yeah the funny thing is I
莎士比亚是的，有趣的 是我
get so much crap for calling you
得到 这么多废话给 你 打电话
Shakespearean
莎士比亚
I didn't even I didn't even realize what
我甚至没有意识到什么
a monumental decision it was because
这是一个巨大的决定 ，因为
five minutes later I read that's a link
五分钟后， 我读到这是一个链接
to my message back on Twitter where
我在Twitter上的消息在哪里
people were already discussing on
人们已经在讨论 上
Twitter guido resigned as the BD FL
Twitter guido辞去了BD FL的职务
and I had I had posted it on an internal
我曾把它贴在内部
forum that I thought was only read by
我认为只能阅读的论坛
core developers so I thought I would at
核心开发人员，所以我想我 会
least have one day before the news would
至少有一天新闻报道
sort of get out the on your own aspect I
排序走出 你 自己 的 方面我
had also an element of quite it was
也有一个相当的元素
quite a powerful element of the
相当强大的 元素
uncertainty that lies ahead but can you
前方的不确定性， 但你可以
also just briefly talk about you know
也只是简单地谈谈你知道
like for example I play guitar as a
例如像 我弹 吉他 作为
hobby for fun and whenever I play people
爱好乐趣 ，每当我玩人
are super positive so super friendly
非常积极， 所以非常 友好
they're like this is awesome this is
他们就像这样真棒
great but sometimes I enter as an
伟大， 但有时我作为一个进入
outside observer I enter the programming
外部观察者我进入编程
community and there seems to some
社区似乎有些
sometimes be camps on whatever the topic
无论有什么话题，有时候都会有阵营
and and the two camps the two or plus
和两个或两个以上的营地
camps are often pretty harsh are
营地往往相当苛刻
criticizing the opposing camps as an
批评对立的阵营作为一个
onlooker I may be totally wrong on this
旁观者我可能 完全 错 了
yeah well because like wars are sort of
是的很好，因为喜欢战争有几分
a favorite activity in the programming
编程中最喜欢的活动
community and what is the psychology
社区和心理学是什么
behind that is is that okay for a
这背后是可以 的
healthy community to have is that is
健康社区就是 这样
that a productive force ultimately for
最终的生产力
the evolution of the language well if
语言的演变 如果
everybody is betting each other on the
每个人都在互相打赌
back and never telling the truth yes it
背部和从来没有说 真话是 它
would not be a good thing I think there
不会是 我觉得有 好 东西
is a middle ground where sort of being
是一个 中间 地带排序 是 哪里
nasty to each other is not okay but
彼此讨厌不好，但是
there there is is a middle ground where
那里有 一个中间地带
there is healthy ongoing criticism and
有持续健康的 批评和批评
feedback that is very productive and you
反馈非常有成效 和你
you mean at every level you see that I
你的意思是在每个级别，你看到我
mean someone proposes to fix a very
意味着有人建议修理一个
small issue in a codebase chances are
小问题一个代码库机会
that some reviewer will sort of respond
有些评论家会做出回应
by saying well actually you can do it
通过说得好你实际上可以做到这一点
better the other way right when it comes
当它到来时， 另一种方式更好
to
至
deciding on the future of the Python
决定Python的未来
core developer community we now have I
核心开发人员社区我们现在拥有
think five or six competing proposals
想想五六个竞争提案
for a constitution so that future do you
一个宪法，以便你的未来
have a fear of that future do you have a
害怕未来你有没有
hope for that future I'm not very
希望未来我不是 很好
confident about that future it by and
对它的未来充满信心
large I think that the debate has been
我 觉得 辩论已经过去了
very healthy and productive and I
非常健康和富有成效，我
actually when when I wrote that
实际上当我写这篇文章的时候
resignation email I knew that that
辞职电子邮件 我知道 那个
Python was in a very good spot and that
蟒蛇是在一个非常好的点和
the Python core development community
Python核心开发社区
that the group of fifty or a hundred
那组五十或一百
people who sort of write or review most
最有写作或评论的人
of the code that goes into Python those
那些进入Python的代码
people get along very well most of the
人相处得很好大部分
time a large number of different areas
时间大量不同的领域
of expertise are represented different
专业知识代表 不同
levels of experience in the Python core
Python核心的经验水平
deaf community different levels of
聋人群体不同层次的
experience completely outside in
完全在外面体验
software development in general large
软件开发一般很大
systems small systems embedded systems
系统小 系统嵌入式系统
so I I felt okay resigning because I
所以 我 觉得 可以辞职，因为我
knew that that the community can really
知道社区可以 真的
take care of itself and out of a grab
照顾好自己，抓住机会
bag of future future developments let me
未来的 未来发展 包 让我
ask if you can comment maybe on all very
问你是否可以对所有人发表评论
quickly concurrent programming parallel
快速并发编程并行
computing async IL these are things that
计算异步 IL就是这些东西
people have expressed hope complained
人们表示希望抱怨
about whatever have discussed on reddit
关于reddit上讨论的内容
async i also the parallelization in
async 我也是并行化
general packaging i was totally clueless
一般包装我完全无能为力
on this I just used piston install stuff
在这我只是使用活塞 安装的东西
but apparently this paper and in poetry
但显然这篇 论文和诗歌
there's these dependency packaging
有这些依赖包装
systems that manage dependencies and so
该管理依赖等系统
on there
在那里
urging and there's a lot of confusion
敦促，并有很多混乱
about what's what's the right thing to
关于什么是 正确的事情
use then also functional programming the
然后使用函数式编程
the ever you know the the are we're
你永远都知道我们是谁
going to get more functional programming
将获得更多功能性编程
or not this kind of this kind of idea
或不是这种这种 想法 的
and of course the the gill is a
当然，鳃是一个
connected to the parallelization I
连接到并行化I
suppose the global interpreter lock
假设全局解释器锁定
problem can you just comment on
问题你能评论一下吗？
whichever you want to comment on well
无论你想评论什么
let's take the gill and paralyzation and
让我们采取刺激和麻痹
async io as one one topic I'm not that
async io 作为一个主题我不是那个
hopeful that Python will develop into a
希望Python能够发展成为一个
sort of high concurrency high
有点高并发性
parallelism language that's sort of the
并行语言就是那种
the way the language is designed the way
语言 的设计 方式 的途径
most users use the language the way the
大多数用户使用语言的方式
language is implemented all make that a
语言实现所有使得 a
pretty unlikely future so you think it
不太可能的未来，所以你想
might not even need to really the way
甚至可能并不 需要真正的方式
people use it it might not be a
人们使用它可能 不是 一个
something that should be a of Greek I
东西 应该是一个希腊的我
think I think async IO is a special case
我认为async IO是一个特例
because it sort of allows overlapping IO
因为它允许重叠IO
and only IO
而且只有IO
and that is is a sort of best practice
这是一种最佳实践
of supporting very high throughput IO
支持非常高的吞吐量IO
many collections per second I'm not
每秒 许多 收藏品我不是
worried about that I think async IO will
担心我认为异步IO会
evolve there are a couple of competing
演变有几个竞争对手
packages we have some very smart people
我们有一些非常聪明的 人
who are sort of pushing us in sort of to
谁有点 推动我们
make async IL better parallel computing
使异步IL更好地并行计算
I think that Python is not the language
我认为 Python不是语言
for that there are there are ways to
为此， 有办法
work around it but you sort of you can't
解决它，但你有点不能
expect to write an algorithm in Python
期望用Python编写算法
and have a compiler or
并有一个编译器或
paralyzed that what you can do is use a
瘫痪你可以做的就是用a
package like numpy and they're a bunch
包像numpy ，他们是一堆
of other very powerful packages that
其他非常强大的软件包
sort of use all the CPUs available
使用所有可用的CPU
because you tell the package here's the
因为你告诉这里的包裹了
data here's the abstract operation to
这里的数据是抽象操作
apply over it go at it and then then
适用于它然后再去
we're back in the c++ world but those
我们回到了c ++世界，但那些
packages are themselves implemented
包本身就是实现的
usually in c++ that's right that's so
通常在c ++中，这是正确的
that's where Tenzin phoned all these
这就是丹增给 所有这些 打电话的地方
acts just come in where they paralyze
行为 刚进入他们瘫痪的地方
across GPUs for example they take care
例如，它们在GPU之间保持谨慎
of that fit so in terms of packaging can
那么适合所以在 包装方面 可以
you comment on this yeah my it packaging
你评论这是我的包装
has always been my least favorite topic
一直是我最不喜欢的话题
it's it's it's a really tough problem
这是一个非常棘手的问题
because the OS and the platform want to
因为操作系统和平台都 想要
own packaging but their packaging
自己的包装， 但包装
solution is not specific to a language
解决方案并非特定于某种语言
like if you take Linux there are two
就像你拿Linux一样，有两个
competing packaging solutions for Linux
适用于Linux的竞争包装解决方案
or for UNIX in in general and but they
或者一般用于UNIX ，但他们
all work across all languages and
在所有语言的所有工作，
several languages like node JavaScript
几种语言，如节点JavaScript
and Ruby and Python all have their own
而Ruby 和Python 都有自己的
packaging solutions that only work
包装解决方案，只有 工作
within the ecosystem of that language
在该语言的生态系统内
well what should you use that is a tough
那么你应该使用什么是一个艰难的
problem my own own approach is I use the
问题我自己的方法是我用的
system packaging system to install
系统包装系统安装
Python and I use the Python packaging
Python和我使用Python包装
system then to install third party
系统然后安装第三方
Python packages that's what most people
Python包是大多数人的意思
do
做
ten years ago Python packaging was
十年前， Python包装是
really a terrible situation nowadays pip
真的是现在糟糕的情况
is the future there is there is a
在未来有没有 一个
separate ecosystem for numerical and
数字和数据的独立生态系统
scientific Python Python based on
基于Python的科学Python Python
anaconda those two can live together I
蟒蛇那两个可以住在一起我
don't think there is a need for more
不要以为 需要更多
than that great so that's that's
比那更好，所以就是这样
packaging that's well at least for me
包装对我来说至少是好的
that's that's where I've been extremely
这就是我 非常的地方
happy I didn't I didn't even know this
快乐 我没有，我甚至不知道这一点
was an issue until it's brought up well
是一个 问题，直到 它提升良好
in interest of time I mean sort of
为了时间的利益， 我的意思 是
skipped through a million other
跳过 了其他一百万人
questions I have so I watched the five
我有问题， 所以我看了 五个
hour five five and a half hour oral
小时五点五个半小时口服
history they've done with the Computer
他们用计算机做过的历史
History Museum and the nice thing about
历史博物馆和好事
it it gave this because of the linear
它因为线性而给出了这个
progression of the interview he gave
他给出的采访进展
this feeling of a life you know a life
这种 生活的 感觉， 你懂得生活
well-lived with interesting things in it
生活中 有趣的东西
sort of a pretty I would say a good
有点 漂亮我会 说好
spend of of this little existence we
花费这个小小的存在我们
have on earth so outside of your family
在 你的家庭 以外的地方
looking back what about this journey are
回顾这次旅程是什么
you really proud of their moments that
你为他们的时刻感到骄傲
stand out accomplishments ideas is it
脱颖而出成就的想法 是它
the creation of Python itself that
Python本身的创建
stands out as a thing that you look back
站出来 为你回头看的事
and say damn I did pretty good there
并说该死的我在那里做得很好
well I would say that Python is
好吧，我会说Python是
definitely the best thing I've ever done
绝对是我做过的最好的事情
and I
和我
I wouldn't sort of say just the creation
我不会仅仅说创作
of Python but the way I sort of raised
Python的方式，但我提出的方式
by farm like a baby
像小孩一样的农场
I didn't just conceive a child but I
我不只是设想一个孩子而是我
raised the child and now I'm setting the
抚养孩子，现在我正在设置
child free in the world and I've set up
世界上没有孩子，我已经成立了
the child to to sort of be able to take
孩子到 那种能够 采取
care of himself and I'm very proud of
照顾自己 ，我很 自豪
that and as the announcer of Monty
那个 和作为蒙蒂的播音员
Python's Flying Circus used to say and
Python的飞行马戏团曾经说过和
now for something completely different
现在完全不同的东西
do you have a favorite Monty Python
你有一个最喜欢的Monty Python吗？
moment or a moment Hitchhiker's Guide or
片刻或者片刻的Hitchhiker's Guide或者
any other literature show a movie that
任何其他文学都展示了一部电影
cracks you up when you think about it oh
当你想到 它 时会让你 崩溃哦
you can always play me the parrots the
你可以随时给我玩 鹦鹉了
dead parrot sketch oh that's brilliant
死鹦鹉素描哦那太棒了
yeah that's my favorite as well pushing
是的，这也是我最喜欢 推动的
up the daisies
雏菊
okay greeted thank you so much for
好的 ，非常 感谢你
talking with me today lecture there's
今天跟我说话讲课
been a great conversation
是一次很棒的 对话
you
您